CONTACT Information School of Mathematics and Statistics

University of Glasgow University Place Glasgow G12 8QQ United Kingdom

robin.bartlett.math@gmail.com

https://http://robin-bartlett.github.io./

RESEARCH INTERESTS Algebraic number theory, the p-adic Langlands program, and links to geometric representation theory. I am particularly interested in combining tools from integral p-adic Hodge theory and algebraic geometry to study of moduli spaces of p-adic Galois representations.

EMPLOYMENT

University of Glasgow

Rankin-Sneddon fellow, from 2023

University of Münster

Postdoctoral researcher, 2020-2023

Max Planck Institute for Mathematics (Bonn)

Postdoctoral researcher, 2018-2020

EDUCATION

Kings College London and the London School of Geometry and Number Theory

Ph.D. in Mathematics, 2014-2018

Thesis: On the reduction modulo p of crystalline representations

• Supervised by Fred Diamond.

University of Warwick

MMath 2010-2014

• Awarded first class degree.

Papers

- 1. Irreducibility of some crystalline loci with irregular Hodge–Tate weights Submitted 2023
- $2. \ \ Cycles \ relations \ in \ the \ affine \ grassmannian \ and \ applications \ to \ Breuil-M\'ezard \ for \ G-crystalline \ representations$

Submitted 2023

- 3. Explicit Serre weights for GL_2 (with Misja Steinmetz) Submitted 2022.
- 4. Degenerating products of flag varieties and applications to the Breuil-Mézard conjecture

To appear Selecta Mathematica.

- 5. Potential diagonalisability of pseudo-Barsotti-Tate representations Journal de Théorie des Nombres de Bordeaux, Volume 35 (2023) no. 2, pp. 335-371.
- 6. On the irreducible components of some crystalline deformation rings Forum of Mathematics Sigma, Volume 8, 2020, e22.
- 7. Potentially diagonalisable crystalline lifts with controlled Hodge-Tate weights Documenta Mathematica, 26, 795-827, 2021.

8. Inertial and Hodge-Tate weights of crystalline representation Mathematische Annalen, 376(1), 645-681.

Services

- Organised the Summer semester 2022 Oberseminar (study group) on the topic of Modularity lifting theorems.
- Co-organised (with Eugen Hellmann) Münster number theory seminar (Summer
- Co-founded London junion number theory seminar (2016-2017)
- Referee for journals including Algebra and Number theory, Forum of Math Pi, Ann. Sci. de l'ENS, J. de l'Ecole Poly. Math, J. Théor. Nombres Bordeaux, Documenta Mathematica, and Math. Res. Lett.

Grants

2016

Applied for and was awarded funding by King's College London Global research grant to support a visit to Professor Frank Calegari and Professor Matthew Emerton at University of Chicago. Value: GBP 2000.

- Conference talks Journées Arithmétiques 2023, Nancy (July 2023)
 - Banff International Research Station, Modularity and Moduli Spaces, CMO Oaxaca (Oct. 2019)

SEMINAR TALKS

- Jussieu, Séminaire Groupes Réductifs et Formes Automorphes (Nov 2023)
- University of Glasgow, Algebra and Number theory seminar (Nov 2023)
- Queen Mary Number theory seminar (July 2023)
- University of Münster (Sep 2022)
- SUSTech, China (Mar. 2022)
- Université Paris 13 (Feb. 2022)
- University of Chicago Number theory seminar (Oct. 2021)
- Queen Mary University London (Mar. 2021)
- University of Arizona (Feb. 2021)
- University of Münster (Nov. 2020)
- University of Rennes (cancelled) (Jan. 2020)
- University of Leiden (Dec. 2019)
- Essen Arithmetic Geometry Research Seminar (Apr. 2019)
- Max Planck Institute for Mathematics Number Theory Seminar (Apr. 2019)
- Max Planck Institute for Mathematics Oberseminar (Nov. 2018)
- University of Purdue Automorphic Forms and Representation Theory Seminar (May 2018)
- University of Chicago Number Theory Seminar (May 2018)
- Junior London Number Theory seminar (Jan. 2018)
- Junior London Number Theory seminar (Oct. 2016)
- London Number Theory Study groups (2015 2018, at least one talk a term)

AWARDS

2013

Awarded funding from the University of Warwick for a summer research project supervised by Dr. Damiano Testa. Project Title: Galois conjugate polynomials. Value: GBP 1000.

2012

Awarded funding from the University of Warwick for a summer research project supervised by Dr. Daan Krammer. Project Title: The Braid group of \mathbb{Z}^n . Value: GBP 1000.

Teaching EXPERIENCE

University of Münster

Masters course: Deformation theory of Galois representations (Winter semester 2021/22)

• Course aimed at masters and Phd students.

King's College London

Teaching Assistant (2016-2018)

• Ran tutorials for classes of 10-20 first and second year undergraduates (Elementary Number Theory, Linear Methods, Geometry, Curves and Surfaces, Introduction to abstract algebra).

University of Warwick

First year tutor (2013-2014)

• Tutored a group of 5 first year mathematics students over the course of a year. Graded their assignments for analysis, linear algebra, number theory and abstract algebra courses.

King's College London Mathematics School

Class tutor (2017-2018)

• Taught two groups of 16-17 year old students mathematical problem solving classes.

Languages English (native), French (reading), German (intermediate).